<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Firefox on Emain Ablach</title>
    <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/tags/firefox/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Firefox on Emain Ablach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://quinoa42.github.io/en/tags/firefox/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Open tridactyl&#39;s external editor in a new tmux window</title>
      <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/tridactyl-editorcmd-with-tmux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/tridactyl-editorcmd-with-tmux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tridactyl/tridactyl&#34;&gt;Tridactyl&lt;/a&gt; has been a decent replacement for &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/vimperator/vimperator-labs&#34;&gt;Vimperator&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/5digits/dactyl&#34;&gt;Pentadactyl&lt;/a&gt; for me since I said goodbye to the XUL extensions. It supports the invocation of external editor (I mean Vim, of course) in its own insert mode pretty well, but the default behavior is to open Vim in a new terminal emulator window. Considering that I&#39;m using &lt;code&gt;tmux&lt;/code&gt; for most of the time, I start to wondering if I could do some tweak with the &lt;code&gt;editorcmd&lt;/code&gt; so that instead of a new terminal emulator window, a termporary tmux window will be opened.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move to Firefox 57 or going back to ESR?</title>
      <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/whimsia/move-to-fx57/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/whimsia/move-to-fx57/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As the so-called next generation of Firefox, 57, has become available as the nightly version, the death of XUL is no longer far away. As the &lt;a href=&#34;https://wiki.mozilla.org/RapidRelease/Calendar&#34;&gt;Calendar&lt;/a&gt; suggests, as soon as 2017-11-14 Firefox 57 will become the stable released version, and ESR will become the only version that supports the dying XUL addons. While &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/qutebrowser/qutebrowser&#34;&gt;qutebrowser&lt;/a&gt; could be a solution to save my way of exploring, it is still in alpha development and lacks some of my must-have features. So the problem is clear: whether to embrace the brand new Firefox 57 or stay back with Firefox ESR (52).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>