<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vim on Emain Ablach</title>
    <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/tags/vim/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vim on Emain Ablach</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://quinoa42.github.io/en/tags/vim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Set up haskell-ide-engine and xmonad</title>
      <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/hie-and-xmonad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/hie-and-xmonad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I have tons of time during this break, I decided to &lt;a href=&#34;http://learnyouahaskell.com/&#34;&gt;learn myself a haskell&lt;/a&gt; and as a way to apply what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned, I&amp;rsquo;ve planed to switch from &lt;a href=&#34;https://awesomewm.org&#34;&gt;awesomeWM&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&#34;https://xmonad.org&#34;&gt;xmonad&lt;/a&gt;. Besides, I&amp;rsquo;ve being troubled with my awesome config&amp;rsquo;s memory leak, which I haven&amp;rsquo;t got the chance to look deeply into, so this might be a good chance to give xmonad a try. However, it spent me a while figuring out how to set the dev environment for xmonad.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Auto-complete user-defined LaTeX packages and classes with Vimtex</title>
      <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/vimtex-user-defined-completion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/vimtex-user-defined-completion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/lervag/vimtex&#34;&gt;vimtex&lt;/a&gt; is one of the most commonly used LaTeX plugin (which is also what I use) in the vim community that supports auto-completion, conceal, synctex pdf preview, and many other modern features. In the last few months after I switched to Linux, the macros I defined in my LaTeX template has grown to such an extent that I have to move them into separate packages and classes. Doing so is &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Creating%5FPackages&#34;&gt;quite easy&lt;/a&gt;, but I got a problem: the commands in my own packages and classes are not in the candidate list of auto-completion!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A workaround that handles after directory scripts for optional packages of Vim8</title>
      <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/vim8-package-opt-after/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/vim8-package-opt-after/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since I started to use Arch Linux, I&amp;rsquo;ve also switched from using plugins such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/junegunn/vim-plug&#34;&gt;vim-plug&lt;/a&gt; to using the native Vim8 packages utility. However, I encountered the problem where if we do &lt;code&gt;packadd SOMEPACKAGE&lt;/code&gt; after (Neo)vim has initialized, and unfortunately if this plugin comes with an &lt;code&gt;after&lt;/code&gt; directory, for example in an &lt;code&gt;autocmd&lt;/code&gt; such as &lt;code&gt;autocmd FileType python vim-textobj-python&lt;/code&gt;, the plugin will not work correctly due to the way Vim8 packages utility handles &lt;code&gt;after&lt;/code&gt; directories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclim Setup</title>
      <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/eclim-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/eclim-setup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I come into the situation where I am forced to use Eclipse, one of those huge IDEs that isolate me from the warm terminal world. However, as a user of (neo)vim, nothing can stop me from doing things in a, at least, vim-like environment. At this moment, one tool comes into my mind: &lt;a href=&#34;http://eclim.org/index.html&#34;&gt;Eclim&lt;/a&gt;, which I have been wondering about since the time when I was still using Windows XP back in my high school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python environment configuration for Neovim</title>
      <link>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/neovim-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quinoa42.github.io/en/oceanus/neovim-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I managed to set up the Python environment for Neovim, which is a little bit tricky, so I decide to write down the problems I overcame so that someone could be helped to configure these easily.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>